bloomz.net 2019-05-28

# Bloomz - Privacy Policy

At Bloomz, we take your privacy very seriously and we have taken every measure so you rest assured your information and your experience at Bloomz stays safe and private. This is why we have updated our Privacy Policy to reflect our commitment with your privacy as well as with common regulation in this matter, like the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA, referred to in our Terms of Service) as well as the Student Privacy Pledge.

Our latest updates to our Privacy Policy below, also include a small summary to the right of the text, so you can easily browse and learn about our commitment to your privacy and security. 

Bloomz is a proud signatory of the Student Privacy Pledge. 

## Information Collected

Like many other services on the internet, Bloomz needs to collect some information from our users and their usage, to be able to provide you with the high quality experience you expect from us - rest assured, we will make every reasonable effort to insure that our service is secure and private in accordance with our promise of service and our policies . The information we collect (whether through our own means or through third parties, as explained below) can be in the form of:   
1) Personal information you submit while creating an account with Bloomz or while using our service;   
2) Automatically collected information; and,   
3) Information from other sources.

| 

## What it means

We need some information to provide you with the best experience possible, and we will make every reasonable effort to keep that information private and secure. There are three types of information we collect: Personal information you submit; automatically collected information; and, information from other sources.  
  
**Personal Information**  
We collect personal information when you register through any of our platforms: website, mobile, or tablet applications (collectively, our "Apps"). Personal information is any information about you that is personally identifiable, such as your name, address, email address or phone number, third-party sign-in information (e.g. Facebook Connect, if applicable), and any other information that is not otherwise publicly available. In addition, if you send email invitations to friends or family to join your Bloomz network, those email addresses are, in some instances, also collected. In addition, there is other information that is stored in our service when either parents or teachers use our apps, including but not limited to: School and class information, including name and address, the student(s) name(s) or age, as well as the information sent over the service, including messages, announcements, images, events and other.

| 

We collect the information you submit while registering for a Bloomz account or through its use, including your school information, posts and messages sent through Bloomz.  
  
**Automatically Collected Information**  
When you use any of our services and apps (web, mobile or other, including when you open our email notifications) we, or our authorized third party service providers (explained below), may also collect information relating to your devices, including your device model, operating system, browser type, unique device identifier, IP address, mobile phone number, mobile network carrier, location, and event information (such as application installations). We may also automatically record certain information from your web browser by using different types of technology, including "clear gifs" or "web beacons." This "automatically collected" information may include your IP address or other device address or ID, web browser and/or device type, the web pages or sites that you visit just before or just after the Service, the pages you view on the Service, and the dates and times that you visit, access, or use the Service. This information is gathered for all users.

| 

We collect information using our own or third party technology (including cookies) to provide you with the best experience possible.  
  
**Information from Other Sources:**  
We may also obtain information, including personally identifiable information, from third parties and sources other than the Service, such as our partners or other service providers, according to their own policies and terms of use. We may also, at your direction, receive information from third party services that provide a mechanism to expose information you have provided to such third parties through the use of an application program interface (API), such as Facebook Connect or the Twitter API. If we combine or associate information from other sources with personally identifiable information that we collect through the Service, we will treat the combined information as personally identifiable information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

| 

We may use other sources (third party) to complement the information you provide and better serve your needs.  
  
**Cookies and Similar Technologies**  
We use cookies (pixel tags, and/or other similar technologies) to collect visitor information. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we send to your computer's hard drive through your web browser. We may use both session cookies and persistent cookies. A session cookie disappears after you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits. Like many services, we use these technologies to tailor the Service for you, and to help the Service work better for you - for example, for authentication, security and site integrity, localization, performance analytics, and other features and services. It is possible to delete cookies or prevent cookies from being used in your browser by turning the feature off. If you do so, you may not be able to use features of our service to their full.

| 

We offer a range of features that use technologies like cookies, pixel tags ("pixels"), device or other identifiers and local storage to provide a seamless and safe experience.  
  
## Authorized Third Parties

Providing a great experience is our outmost priority, but sometimes doing it all on our own is really hard, so we work with third party vendors, service providers, and other partners to help us provide the Service by performing tasks on our behalf. We may need to share or provide information (including personal information) to them to help them perform these business functions, for example sending emails on our behalf, database management services, database hosting, providing customer support software, and security. These service providers do not have the right to use your personal information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us. Additionally, these service providers must adhere to confidentiality and security obligations in a way that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

We may use third-party service providers to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet and on our Apps. They may collect anonymous information about your visits to our Apps and your interaction with our services. They may also use information about your visits to our Apps and other sites and mobile applications to target ads for products and services. For instance, they may collect web log data from you (such as IP address and information about your browser or operating system) or place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads. Through this process, demographic or other interest data may be associated with your browser or device **in a non-personally identifiable manner**. No personally identifiable information is collected in this process. They do not know the name, address, email address, phone number or any personally identifiable information about the user.

We also work with third party service providers to monitor certain pages of our Apps for such purposes as reporting traffic and other advertising statistics. Where authorized by us, these third party providers may use cookies and/or other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous statistics about our visitors. No personally identifiable information is transferred to these third party service providers. This information is collected directly by the third party, and Bloomz does not participate in that data transmission. Information collected by third parties in this manner is subject to that third party's own data collection, use, and disclosure policies.

| 

Sometimes we just need a little help from our friends (and partners). But rest assured we are only sharing information needed to provide our service, and our partners will not use data for any other purpose. Even when we talk to you outside of our service, we don't share any personally identifiable information.  
  
## Use of Information

We use your information for the following general purposes: to operate, maintain, and improve our services, to contact you, for internal business purposes, and to customize any advertising and content you see in our apps. We use third party information you provide to us solely to provide services you specifically request.

We will also use all of the information that you provide and that we collect to understand and analyze the usages trends and preferences of our users, to improve our product, and to create new features and functionality. We may use your information to personalize our services, such as remembering your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you visit the Apps; provide customized advertisements and offer you other relevant products, content, and information; monitor and analyze the effectiveness of our services and third party marketing activities; monitor aggregate site usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages viewed; and track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities.

We will never use students’ personally identifiable information, or collect, use, or share such information for any purposes beyond the authorized educational or school purposes, or as explicitly authorized by the student or parent. We will never target advertisements to students or sell students’ personally identifiable information to third parties for any purpose.

When you invite recipients to join our service, we may contact them regarding our product and Service, using the appropriate form of communication. If they would prefer not to receive our communications, they may opt-out using the "Unsubscribe" or "STOP" instructions contained in those communications. Rest assured that we will not use the email addresses that you enter through email invitations, or your address books through any of our Apps to send marketing communications to your friends and family, unless they sign up for an account on their own and accept our terms and services.

When a teacher invites parents to join their classroom on Bloomz via our SmartInvite feature in our app, the emails entered in the invitation will automatically be opted-in to classroom communications via email. We do this to ensure parents who don't know how to create an account don't miss on important updates from the teacher. Recipients can always opt-out by using the "Unsubscribe" instructions in those communications.

Your accounts also contain a calendar where you can store events and other key dates and details about friends and family. We may send you email reminders of the personalized dates you have entered in this calendar. You may decline to share certain personally identifiable information with us, in which case we may not be able to provide to you some of the features and functionality of the Service. You may update or correct your profile information and preferences at any time by accessing your account preferences page through the Service. Please note that while your changes are reflected promptly in active user databases, we may retain all information you submit for a variety of purposes, including backups and archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, and analytics.

| 

The information we collect serves to run our business and to better tailor the experience for you. Emails of parents invited to join a classroom in Bloomz are automatically opted-in to classroom communications, so parents don't miss on important updates. Any person can opt-out of Bloomz communications following instructions included in those, or adjusting your notification preferences in the apps. Bloomz does NOT serve ads to students or use students personally identifiable information for any other purpose.  
  
**Disclosure of Information**  
We do not sell or disclose your personally identifiable information to nonaffiliated parties except in connection with our services and the operation of our business as explained in this policy and our terms of service. We may disclose your personal information in the following ways: 

  * Any information that you voluntarily choose to include in a publicly accessible area of the Apps, such as a public profile page, will be available to anyone who has access to that content, including other users.
  * We provide personal information to nonaffiliated companies that we engage as contractors or agents to perform services for us, such as administering our websites, systems and software, hosting maintenance, and other such services. These third party service providers may have access to or process your information to the extent it is necessary for them to complete their contractual obligations to us. Generally, these disclosures are made under terms comparable to this policy, and the recipients are limited to using the information the purpose for which it was provided.
  * We may disclose all the information we collect as described above to other companies to: comply with various reporting obligations; for business or marketing purposes; or to assist such parties in understanding our users' interests, habits, and usage patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality available through the Apps.
  * In response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, from law enforcement agencies or state and federal regulators, or as otherwise required by law;
  * To assert or defend our legal rights, including fraud prevention;
  * To protect the rights, property, or safety of other persons;
  * As we deem appropriate to attempt to prevent physical or emotional harm to other persons and/or to their property based on overt or implied threat;
  * In connection with an actual or proposed corporate merger, acquisition, asset purchase, or other transaction or proceeding involving all or part of the business or assets to which the information pertains.

| 

We do not sell your personal information to third parties, and will not share information other than as established in this policy.  
  
## Children's Privacy

Our Apps are not intended for use by children under the age of 13. In fact, they are intended for teacher-parent communication. As part of that process, a teacher may request an individual student to input content that was created by that student, however, in no circumstance does that input become part of the student's profile without teacher approval. We will not knowingly collect personally identifiable information via this site from visitors under the age of 13, other than as previously stated. If we learn that personally identifiable information has been collected on the Service from persons under the age of 13 and without verifiable parental or teacher consent, then we will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. 

| 

We don't collect information from children under 13, thus Bloomz is COPPA compliant.  
  
## COPPA Compliance

|   
  
The [COPPA Rule](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online) was put in place to protect kids' personal information on websites and online services — including apps — that are directed to children under 13. The Rule also applies to a general audience site that knows it's collecting personal information from kids that age. Because Bloomz doesn't collect information from children under 13, other than as previously stated, and any information related to students in Bloomz is knowingly entered by parents or by teachers with permission of the parents, Bloomz is COPPA compliant.

|   
  
If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has obtained an account on the Service, please alert us immediately at [support@bloomz.com](mailto:support@bloomz.com).

|   
  
## Our Commitment to Data Security:

We use certain physical, managerial, and technical safeguards that are designed to improve the integrity and security of your information. As is the case with other online services, however, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or store on the Apps and you do so at your own risk. We also cannot guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards. If we learn of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may post a notice through the Apps if a security breach occurs.

| 

We take serious efforts to protect your information and the data in our service. As with any other online service, it is important you take personal measures to protect your information (like safeguarding your password).  
  
Similarly, although we may allow you to adjust your privacy settings to limit access to your information, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you may choose to share your information. Therefore, we cannot and do not guarantee that information you post on the Apps will not be viewed by unauthorized persons. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Website. You understand and acknowledge that, even after removal, copies of information that you have posted may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if other users have copied or stored such information.

|   
  
## Updates to Privacy Policy

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting updates on this page. Please check back periodically to view any updates. In the event that the modifications materially alter your rights or obligations hereunder, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you of the change via email, if we have one on file, or generate a pop-up or similar notification when you access the Apps for the first time after such material changes are made. Our amended Privacy Policy will automatically take effect 30 days after it is made available through the Apps. If you do not agree with any changes to the Privacy Policy, you may terminate your account and stop using the Apps. Your continued use of the Apps after the revised Privacy Policy has become effective indicates that you have read, understood and agreed to the current version of the Privacy Policy.

| 

We will always let you know by email and/or through our apps when we make significant changes to our Privacy Policy  
  
## Questions and Suggestions

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us at [support@bloomz.com](mailto:support@bloomz.com) or through the feedback link on our Apps.

| 

Email us at [support@bloomz.com](mailto:support@bloomz.com)
